<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Concerns on Data to Dream</title>
    <link>/concerns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concerns on Data to Dream</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/concerns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Police Budget</title>
      <link>/concerns/police-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/concerns/police-budget/</guid>
      <description>Overview Police are the largest expense in the operating budgets for the City of Houston and Harris County. Due to the state’s anti-defund law, local governments face severe restrictions in reducing police spending. The median overall pay for the Houston Police Department during the 2022-2023 fiscal year was $97,792, higher than any other city department.&#xA;Visualizations News City Council approves over $1 billion budget for Houston Police Department without proper public engagement - Shift Press Community Advocates Oppose Increasing Houston Police Budget At City Council Datasets City of Houston Open Finance Data Portal</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surveillance Technology</title>
      <link>/concerns/surveillance-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/concerns/surveillance-technology/</guid>
      <description>Overview The City of Houston, Harris County, and Spring Branch ISD have purchased ShotSpotter, a costly and controversial technology that involves microphones installed in communities that experience gun violence.&#xA;Visualizations Houston Shotspotter map&#xA;SoundSpotter Alerts from 2020-12 - 2023-06&#xA;News Critics say ShotSpotter gunfire alert data is inaccurate, but Houston is spending $3.5M to expand it Houston ShotSpotter program: Are 99 arrests in two years worth it? Houston&amp;rsquo;s gunshot alert system isn&amp;rsquo;t curbing violence but delays police response times, data shows Authorities investigating late response to shooting of George Floyd’s 4-year-old grandniece in South Side Datasets ShotSpotter data - Houston ShotSpotter Data (Houston Police Department) • MuckRock</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traffic Stops</title>
      <link>/concerns/traffic-stops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/concerns/traffic-stops/</guid>
      <description>Overview HPD conducts hundreds of thousands of traffic stops every year, and Houston drivers are far more likely to experience police violence during traffic stops than in other Texas cities. Houston police agencies also frequently conduct dangerous car chases, placing residents at risk.&#xA;Visualizations News Crash &amp;amp; Burn: A Houston Chronicle investigation into police chases &amp;lsquo;The justice system failed us&amp;rsquo;: Jalen Randle&amp;rsquo;s mother decries grand jury decision Datasets TCOLE Traffic Stop Data - Racial Profiling Reports | Texas Commission on Law Enforcement</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
